# **Sedric Ouambo Silatchom**

# https://sedricouambo.github.io/sedric-portfolio

#### **PROFESSIONAL PROFILE**

A professional with 7 years of experience in computer programming and teaching, combined with a solid training in computer science and a strong ability to quickly acquire new knowledge, I am able to work effectively in agile mode, autonomously or as a team perfectly in French and English. I have a strong knowledge of collecting client needs, a strong sense of organization and proven skills in teaching, coding techniques and computer program design.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

CEPI - Collège La Cité, Ottawa, Canada.

## **Artificial Intelligence Developer.**

05/2023 - 08/2023

- · Crafted comprehensive documentation describing the procedures for managing the motion, sound and visual sensors of the robots, allowing a 30% reduction in the time users use to manage robots.
- Programming scripts to allow robots to run a simulated abduction at Collège La Cité, during staff academic year, which increased participant satisfaction by 50%.

Ministry of Secondary Education, Cameroon.

# **Software Developer.**

01/2017 - 05/2022

- Participate in the development of an application for the management and deliberation of official examinations; this will reduce the waiting time for the results of these examinations by more than 50%.
- Participate in the realization of the website of the census of the ministry staff in the decentralized services, with PHP.
- In collaboration with other colleagues, design and implement the KSCHOOL application for school management at the Technical High School of Santchou. Using Java Language and PostgreSQL DBMS.

Government Technical High School, Santchou, Cameroun.

# Computer technical support and Teacher.

01/2015 - 05/2022

- Analyzed, proposed and improved an IT Learning Management System for School, resulting in a 40% reduction in administrative workload and a 25% increase in student engagement.
- · Guided comprehensive technical guidance to colleagues and students, on effective usage of the school computer system; improved system efficiency and reduced support requests by 40%.
- Developed and delivered a comprehensive web programming course focusing on HTML, CSS, JavaScript and MySQL to level 12 students; increased proficiency and productivity by 40% within 3 months.

# **PROJECTS**

- Website for a conference using React and Next.js.
- Python PCAP certification quiz using React and Next.js.
- Modern web app to restaurant using Express.js.

### **CONTACT**

- · 819-319-9747
- · ON, K1Z5R7
- · ouambosedric@gmail.com
- · linkedin.com/in/sedricouambo

#### **SKILLS**

#### Hard Skill:

- Coding (Advanced)
- Debugging (Experienced)
- Software Design and Testing
- · Web and mobile Development

### **Programming Languages:**

· C#, · Python, · Java, · Swift, · Kotlin

#### Web technologies:

- HTML5, · CSS3, · JavaScript
- · React, · Next.js, · Express.js
- PHP; Django

#### Databases:

- · MySQL, · SQL Server, · MongoDB
- · Cassandra, · PostgreSQL

#### **EDUCATION**

Collège La Cité

# **Ontario College Diploma**

**Computer Programming** 

Ottawa, Canada 09/2022 - 04/2024

University of Bamenda - Cameroon

#### Master's degree of Education

Major Computer Science (WES Equivalence available)

Bambili, Cameroon 10/2012 - 07/2014

University of Dschang - Cameroon

### **Bachelor of Computer Science**

Major Computer Science (WES Equivalence available)

Dschang, Cameroon

10/2009 - 07/2012

#### **CERTIFICATES**

- Certified Associate in Python Programming (PCAP).
- Android Certified Developer, v12
- Workplace rescue worker.